<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Lafayette Digital Repository Metadata Dictionary &amp; Creation Guidelines</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Lafayette Digital Repository Metadata Dictionary &amp; Creation Guidelines</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 13:39:37 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Standard Identifier</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/administrative-metadata/standard-identifier/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 09:45:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/administrative-metadata/standard-identifier/</guid><description>Guidelines # The LDR accepts the following types of standard identifiers:
DOI ISBN ISSN From the Work dashboard, use the drop-down menu to select a prefix for the identifier. Then, enter the identifier into the form box at right.
Handles are minted by a server attached to the repository application A Handle ID will be created for all new items added to the LDR If a Handle already exists for the item, enter it as in the template or webform</description></item><item><title>Rights Statement</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/administrative-metadata/rights-statement/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:55:14 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/administrative-metadata/rights-statement/</guid><description>Guidelines # Rights information may be found in the item itself, in the digital project documentation, or in accompanying or supplemental information.
The most common right statements in the LDR are the Public Domain Mark (PDM), In Copyright, and Copyright Undetermined.
For Faculty publications, where the copyright status of a resource is undetermined, always apply the In Copyright (InC) rights statement.
All Creative Commons licenses can only be applied by, or with the permission of, the rights holder.</description></item><item><title>Rights Holder</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/administrative-metadata/rights-holder/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:52:46 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/administrative-metadata/rights-holder/</guid><description>Guidelines # Establishing the identity of the Rights Holders of an item helps when a user has a question about use, reproduction, or whom to contact regarding copyright of the item.
When entering a personal name:
→ use the name format Last, First Middle</description></item><item><title>Note</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/administrative-metadata/note/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:51:29 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/administrative-metadata/note/</guid><description>Guidelines # This property is not visible to public users, only to internal users. To be used for any information important to internal maintenance of records or relevant to the original items, such as administrative, digitization, or decision documentation.</description></item><item><title>Title</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/title/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:39:23 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/title/</guid><description>Guidelines # Every work in the LDR must have one value in the Title property.
If the work has a formal Title, transcribe it as it appears in the original - including capitalization and punctuation.
If no formal or official Title exist, devise a brief descriptive title. Enclose this supplied or devised title in square brackets []
→ A good descriptive title uniquely and specifically describes the resource</description></item><item><title>Subtitle</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/subtitle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:37:49 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/subtitle/</guid><description>Guidelines # Ancillary title information for the resource. A main title is required before subtitle(s) may be used. For example, Mary Shelley uses the alternative title &amp;lsquo;The Modern Prometheus&amp;rsquo; to hint at the theme of her most famous novel &amp;lsquo;Frankenstein&amp;rsquo;; Nick Efford uses the subtitle &amp;lsquo;a practical introduction using Java&amp;rsquo; to qualify the title of his book &amp;lsquo;Digital Image Processing&amp;rsquo;.
Language-tagged Field
→ Use the box next to the right of the property in the Work dashboard to enter the language of the Title value</description></item><item><title>Subject</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/subject/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:31:30 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/subject/</guid><description>Guidelines # In most cases, the item must be read or examined in order to determine subject(s) terms.
In the repository Work dashboard, the Subject property is configured to fetch controlled subject headings from OCLC FAST.
→ FAST (Faceted Application of Subject Terminology) is derived from the Library of Congress Subject Headings, and includes more than 1.7 million authority records that have been optimized for use with Web resources.</description></item><item><title>Sponsor</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/sponsor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:29:53 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/sponsor/</guid><description>Guidelines # This is a collection-level metadata property only.</description></item><item><title>Source</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/source/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:27:36 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/source/</guid><description>Guidelines # The described resource may be derived from the Source resource in whole or in part.
Include as much information about the Source as is known
Where Resource Type = Part of Book (for example, if the described resource is a book chapter, put the title of the book in the Source property.
Identify the related resource by means of a string conforming to a formal identification system, such as a DOI, permalink URI, ISBN, ISSN, or OCLC Number.</description></item><item><title>Resource Type</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/resource-type/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:14:44 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/resource-type/</guid><description>Guidelines # Choose one or more Resource Type values from the controlled list. Select the term or terms that best characterize or describes the resource.
Resource Type Definition Article A self-contained nonfiction prose composition on a particular subject, written by one or more authors who conducted the research and for publication in an academic or scholarly journal, or other serial publication. Audio A resource primarily intended to be heard.</description></item><item><title>Research Assistance</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/research-assistance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:12:44 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/research-assistance/</guid><description>Guidelines # For example, this field can be used to hold the names of College students and faculty
responsible for metadata creation, translations, research, scanning, color correction, etc. It
could also list names of experts who have provided content, criticisms, and other forms of
assistance for a particular image.</description></item><item><title>Requested By</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/requested-by/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:11:16 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/requested-by/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Repository Location</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/repository-location/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:09:31 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/repository-location/</guid><description>Guidelines # Use this property to contain information about the original location of the physical item, or the external repository where a digital resource may be stored.</description></item><item><title>Related Resource</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/related-resource/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:08:07 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/related-resource/</guid><description>Identify related resources with the title of the related materials, and include a unique identifier (such as a DOI or ISBN) and a permalink URI if one exists.
Unless directed to do so by a project lead or supervisor, it is not necessary to conduct research to locate related resources.</description></item><item><title>Publisher</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/publisher/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:04:29 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/publisher/</guid><description>Guidelines # Examples of a Publisher include a person, an organization, a corporate body, a government agency, a university, a publishing house, etc.
Information about the Publisher of a Work may be found on:
→ a copyright page or colophon
→ a logo on a photograph, map, or book
When possible, consult an authority file to locate the controlled form of the name
→ for example, the Library of Congress Name Authority File</description></item><item><title>Physical Medium</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/physical-medium/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:01:56 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/physical-medium/</guid><description>Guidelines # Use this property to describe the medium of the original physical resource from which the digital resource was derived, if applicable.
NOT to be used to describe the file format of a digitized or born-digital resource.
→ If a resource is born-digital, leave this property blank. Examples # silver gelatin print microfiche tempera on canvas</description></item><item><title>Organization</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/organization/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:59:49 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/organization/</guid><description>Guidelines # This property is intended for use with faculty, staff, and institutional publications, administrative materials, etc.
Along with the Academic Department and Division properties, this value provides a consistent reference to the unit that is responsible for the creation or authorship of the resource.
Can be used to contain the name of a partner institution that owns the physical item, if not held by Lafayette College Libraries or Special Collections.</description></item><item><title>Location</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/location/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:48:06 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/location/</guid><description>Guidelines # Spatial coverage is about the content of item and refers to a geographic location, and not to proper place names such as buildings or human-created landmarks.
In the repository Work dashboard, this property is configured to fetch controlled geographic location data from the GeoNames webservice .
→ Enter the geographic location into the form, then select from the list retrieved from GeoNames. This populates the value with a URI for the location, which serves as linked geographic data.</description></item><item><title>Language</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/language/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:25:20 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/language/</guid><description>Guidelines # Enter each language name into the box in the form and click to select the appropriate suggested value.</description></item><item><title>Keyword</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/keyword/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:15:23 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/keyword/</guid><description>Guidelines # In many cases, the item must be read or examined in order to determine appropriate keyword(s). Keywords serve two main functions: helping users locate the resource being described, and grouping similar resources in relevant search results.
Use lowercase, unless the keywords are proper nouns
Use plural forms of keywords, unless there isn’t a logical plural form
Keep keywords or phrases short</description></item><item><title>Issued</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/issued/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:04:22 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/issued/</guid><description>Required for Publication data model resources.
Guidelines # Use for published materials, e.g. articles, book chapters
Write dates Year-Month-Day, separating the sections with a hyphen
→ If only partial dates are known, follow the same basic format:
Examples # YYYY-MM-DD YYYY-MM YYYY</description></item><item><title>Inscription</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/inscription/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:02:10 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/inscription/</guid><description>Guidelines # Use for any handwritten and/or transcribed printed text on a resource, such as a postcard, photograph, or scrapbook page.</description></item><item><title>Extent</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/extent/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 15:56:25 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/extent/</guid><description>Guidelines # Write duration in timestamp format, Hour:Minute:Second
For digital size, use the byte abbreviation, e.g. KB, MB, GB, TB
When describing physical size, always include the unit of measurement.
Examples # 1 print : image 31.1 x 22.4 cm., on mount 31.7 x 23.2 cm. 06:18:57 24 x 19.5 cm. 14.4 MB</description></item><item><title>Editor</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/editor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 15:53:31 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/editor/</guid><description>Guidelines # In most cases, the Editor name(s) can be found in the title page, colophon, or any other information source that also includes Creator name(s).
When possible, consult an authority file to locate the controlled form of the name
→ for example, the Library of Congress Name Authority File
the Getty Research Institute Union List of Artist Names
When entering a personal name:</description></item><item><title>Donor</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/donor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 15:49:52 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/donor/</guid><description>Guidelines # Name of donor(s) as provided in deed of gift, catalog record, finding aid, etc.</description></item><item><title>Division</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/division/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 15:38:57 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/division/</guid><description>Guidelines # This property is intended for use with faculty, staff, and institutional publications, administrative materials, etc.
Along with the Academic Department and Institution properties, this value provides a consistent reference to the unit that is responsible for the creation or authorship of the resource.
Begin typing the value of the department into the form and select from the local controlled list:
→ Asian Studies</description></item><item><title>Description</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/description/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 15:35:03 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/description/</guid><description>Guidelines # In most cases, the item will have to be read or examined in order to determine a description of the content. The Description should contain details about the people, places, events, or themes depicted in or discussed by the resource.
Some best practices for writing item descriptions include:
Form complete sentences with proper grammar, ending with a period.
Take the Description directly from the source when possible.</description></item><item><title>Data Scope Note</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/data-scope-note/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 15:32:15 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/data-scope-note/</guid><description>Guidelines # When used in legacy EAIC collections, this property contains printed information on the backs of postcards, including indicia, that is relevant to dating the postcard itself (not the image reproduced in that postcard).</description></item><item><title>Date</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/date/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 15:27:35 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/date/</guid><description>Guidelines # Record the date in ISO 8601 /EDTF format.
→ The LDR application will display EDTF date in a human-readable format in the public-facing user interface.
For published materials, use the Issued property instead.
Avoid using abbreviations or Latin terms for dates.
Examples # Encoding Date field value (encoded EDTF) Display Date yyyy 1861 1861 yyyy-mm 2011-07 July 2011 yyyy-mm-dd 1451-04-22 April 22, 1451 yyyy-mm-dd/yyyy-mm-dd 1992-06-10/1999-07-31 June 10, 1992 to July 31, 1999 yyyy~/yyyy~ 1910~/1915~ Circa 1910 to circa 1915 yyyy~ 33 Circa 33</description></item><item><title>Creator</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/creator/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 14:51:23 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/creator/</guid><description>Guidelines # Creators include any entity that was centrally involved in creating the item.
Only include entities that are primarily responsible for the creation of the item.
→ “secondary creators” (entities related to the item but not directly related to its creation) should be entered in the Contributor property instead.
Enter information for all known Creators, with names separated by a pipe character | and no spaces.</description></item><item><title>Contributor</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/contributor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 14:35:55 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/contributor/</guid><description>Guidelines # Use this property to enter the names of entities that contributed to the creation of the work, but are not the primary creator.
Enter information for all known Contributors, with multiple names separated by a pipe character | and no spaces.
When possible, consult an authority file to locate the controlled form of the name
→ for example, the Library of Congress Name Authority File</description></item><item><title>Bibliographic Citation</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/bibliographic-citation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 13:48:39 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/bibliographic-citation/</guid><description>Guidelines # Take the Citation directly from the source if possible. For example, many Citations for academic journal articles are supplied by the publisher on a title page, in a page header or footer, or in accompanying or supplemental information.
Enter the Citation exactly as it appears in the source.
If no Citation is supplied by the publisher, use the following format:
Author LastName, Author FirstName.</description></item><item><title>Alternative Title</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/alternative-title/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 13:42:28 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/alternative-title/</guid><description>Guidelines # Use for other forms of the title.
For example, use for versions of the title in languages other than English.
→ Use the box to the right of the property in the Work dashboard to enter the language of the Title value
If the resource is an article or book chapter derived from a monograph series, use Alternative Title to contain the monograph series title.</description></item><item><title>Associated Date</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/associated-date/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 13:14:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/associated-date/</guid><description>Guidelines # When used in legacy EAIC collections, this property refers to the date of an event documented in the photographic image, and later reproduced in an album or postcard.
Record the associated date in ISO 8601 /EDTF format.
→ The LDR application will display EDTF date in a human-readable format in the public-facing user interface.
Avoid using abbreviations or Latin terms for dates.</description></item><item><title>Academic Department</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/academic-department/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 12:59:57 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/academic-department/</guid><description>Guidelines # This property is intended for use with faculty, staff, and institutional publications, administrative materials, etc.
Along with the Division and Institution properties, this value provides a consistent reference to the unit that is responsible for the creation or authorship of the resource.
Begin typing the value of the department into the form and select from the local controlled list:
→ Administrative Content
→ Africana Studies</description></item><item><title>Abstract</title><link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/abstract/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 13:29:08 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/abstract/</guid><description>Guidelines # Take the Abstract directly from the source if possible – for example, most Abstracts for academic journal articles are supplied by the publisher.</description></item></channel></rss>