<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Descriptive on Lafayette Digital Repository Metadata Dictionary &amp; Creation Guidelines</title>
    <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Descriptive on Lafayette Digital Repository Metadata Dictionary &amp; Creation Guidelines</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 14:08:03 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Title</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/title/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:39:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/title/</guid>
      <description>Title #     Condition Value     Definition The name given to the resource. (DCMI )   Required? Yes   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #  Every work in the LDR must have one value in the Title property.
  If the work has a formal Title, transcribe it as it appears in the original - including capitalization and punctuation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subtitle</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/subtitle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:37:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/subtitle/</guid>
      <description>Subtitle #     Condition Value     Definition An explanatory title of a publication.   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #  Ancillary title information for the resource. A main title is required before subtitle(s) may be used. For example, Mary Shelley uses the alternative title &amp;lsquo;The Modern Prometheus&amp;rsquo; to hint at the theme of her most famous novel &amp;lsquo;Frankenstein&amp;rsquo;; Nick Efford uses the subtitle &amp;lsquo;a practical introduction using Java&amp;rsquo; to qualify the title of his book &amp;lsquo;Digital Image Processing&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subject</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/subject/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:31:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/subject/</guid>
      <description>Subject #     Condition Value     Definition Formal, controlled subject terms or headings that describe the people, organizations, events, themes, or topics of the resource.   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #  In most cases, the item must be read or examined in order to determine subject(s) terms.
 In the repository Work dashboard, the Subject property is configured to fetch controlled subject headings from OCLC FAST.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sponsor</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/sponsor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:29:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/sponsor/</guid>
      <description>Sponsor #     Condition Value     Definition A person or organization that supports the collection, e.g. through a
pledge, or financial contribution.   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #  This is a collection-level metadata property only.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Source</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/source/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:27:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/source/</guid>
      <description>Source #     Condition Value     Definition A related resource from which the described resource is derived.   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #  The described resource may be derived from the Source resource in whole or in part.
  Include as much information about the Source as is known
  Where Resource Type = Part of Book (for example, if the described resource is a book chapter, put the title of the book in the Source property.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resource Type</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/resource-type/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:14:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/resource-type/</guid>
      <description>Resource Type #     Condition Value     Definition The nature or genre of the resource. Type terms describe general categories, functions, genres, or aggregation levels for content. Select at least one value from the local controlled vocabulary.   Required? Yes   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #  Choose one or more Resource Type values from the controlled list. Select the term or terms that best characterize or describes the resource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Assistance</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/research-assistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:12:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/research-assistance/</guid>
      <description>Research Assistance #     Condition Value     Definition Name of an agent for research in support of a resource.   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #  For example, this field can be used to hold the names of College students and faculty
responsible for metadata creation, translations, research, scanning, color correction, etc. It
could also list names of experts who have provided content, criticisms, and other forms of</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Requested By</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/requested-by/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:11:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/requested-by/</guid>
      <description>Requested By #     Condition Value     Definition The faculty or community member that requested an item or
collection (i.e. from Archives &amp;amp; Special Collections) be scanned
and ingested into the repository.   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Repository Location</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/repository-location/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:09:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/repository-location/</guid>
      <description>Repository Location #     Condition Value     Definition Institution, organization, or collection where the original object is
housed and made accessible.   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #  Use this property to contain information about the original location of the physical item, or the external repository where a digital resource may be stored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Related Resource</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/related-resource/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:08:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/related-resource/</guid>
      <description>Related Resource #     Condition Value     Definition Further information about another resource, which is related to the resource being described.   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Identify related resources with the title of the related materials, and include a unique identifier (such as a DOI or ISBN) and a permalink URI if one exists.
 Unless directed to do so by a project lead or supervisor, it is not necessary to conduct research to locate related resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publisher</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/publisher/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:04:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/publisher/</guid>
      <description>Publisher #     Condition Value     Definition An entity responsible for making the resource available. The publisher of the original work.   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #  Examples of a Publisher include a person, an organization, a corporate body, a government agency, a university, a publishing house, etc.
  Information about the Publisher of a Work may be found on:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physical Medium</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/physical-medium/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:01:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/physical-medium/</guid>
      <description>Physical Medium #     Condition Value     Definition A physical material or carrier. Examples include paper, canvas, or DVD.   Required? No   Repeatable? No    Guidelines #  Use this property to describe the medium of the original physical resource from which the digital resource was derived, if applicable.
 NOT to be used to describe the file format of a digitized or born-digital resource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organization</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:59:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/organization/</guid>
      <description>Organization #     Condition Value     Definition A kind of Agent corresponding to social institutions such as companies, colleges, universities, historical societies, museums, etc.   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #  This property is intended for use with faculty, staff, and institutional publications, administrative materials, etc.
  Along with the Academic Department and Division properties, this value provides a consistent reference to the unit that is responsible for the creation or authorship of the resource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Location</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/location/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:48:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/location/</guid>
      <description>Location #     Condition Value     Definition Spatial characteristics and/or cover of the resource content. Spatial topic and spatial applicability may be a named place or a location specified by its geographic coordinates.   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #    Spatial coverage is about the content of item and refers to a geographic location, and not to proper place names such as buildings or human-created landmarks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/language/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:25:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/language/</guid>
      <description>Language #     Condition Value     Definition A language of the resource content.   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #  Enter each language name into the box in the form and click to select the appropriate suggested value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keyword</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/keyword/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:15:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/keyword/</guid>
      <description>Keyword #     Condition Value     Definition Words or tags used to describe what the content is about. Keywords use natural language; they do not conform to any controlled vocabulary or subject heading classification.   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #  In many cases, the item must be read or examined in order to determine appropriate keyword(s). Keywords serve two main functions: helping users locate the resource being described, and grouping similar resources in relevant search results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Issued</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/issued/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:04:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/issued/</guid>
      <description>Issued #     Condition Value     Definition Date of formal issuance (e.g. publication) of the resource   Required? Yes (for Publication data model resources)   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #    Use for published materials, e.g. articles, book chapters
  Write dates Year-Month-Day, separating the sections with a hyphen
→ If only partial dates are known, follow the same basic format:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inscription</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/inscription/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 10:02:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/inscription/</guid>
      <description>Inscription #     Condition Value     Definition Text of an inscription on the object   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #  Use for any handwritten and/or transcribed printed text on a resource, such as a postcard, photograph, or scrapbook page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extent</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/extent/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 15:56:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/extent/</guid>
      <description>Extent #     Condition Value     Definition The dimensions of the resource, e.g. physical or digital size, duration.   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #    Write duration in timestamp format, Hour:Minute:Second
  For digital size, use the byte abbreviation, e.g. KB, MB, GB, TB
  When describing physical size, always include the unit of measurement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Editor</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 15:53:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/editor/</guid>
      <description>Editor #     Condition Value     Definition A person having managerial and sometimes policy-making responsibility for the editorial part of a publishing firm or of a newspaper, magazine, or other publication.   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #  In most cases, the Editor name(s) can be found in the title page, colophon, or any other information source that also includes Creator name(s).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Donor</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/donor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 15:49:52 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/donor/</guid>
      <description>Donor #     Condition Value     Definition &amp;ldquo;A statement of any changes in ownership and custody of the resource since its creation that are significant for its authenticity, integrity, and interpretation.&amp;rdquo; (DCMI )   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #  Name of donor(s) as provided in deed of gift, catalog record, finding aid, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Division</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/division/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 15:38:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/division/</guid>
      <description>Division #     Condition Value     Definition A major unit or section within a larger organization.   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #  This property is intended for use with faculty, staff, and institutional publications, administrative materials, etc.
  Along with the Academic Department and Institution properties, this value provides a consistent reference to the unit that is responsible for the creation or authorship of the resource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Description</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/description/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 15:35:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/description/</guid>
      <description>Description #     Condition Value     Definition An account of the resource content.   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #  In most cases, the item will have to be read or examined in order to determine a description of the content. The Description should contain details about the people, places, events, or themes depicted in or discussed by the resource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Scope Note</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/data-scope-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 15:32:15 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/data-scope-note/</guid>
      <description>Date Scope Note #     Condition Value     Definition A note explaining the coverage, specialized usage, and/or rules for assigning the Date value.   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #  When used in legacy EAIC collections, this property contains printed information on the backs of postcards, including indicia, that is relevant to dating the postcard itself (not the image reproduced in that postcard).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Date</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/date/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 15:27:35 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/date/</guid>
      <description>Date #     Condition Value     Definition Date associated with the creation of the original resource.   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #    Record the date in ISO 8601 /EDTF  format.
→ The LDR application will display EDTF date in a human-readable format in the public-facing user interface.
  For published materials, use the Issued property instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creator</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/creator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 14:51:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/creator/</guid>
      <description>Creator #     Condition Value     Definition A person, agency, organization or other entity primarily responsible for creating the intellectual content of the resource.   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #  Creators include any entity that was centrally involved in creating the item.
  Only include entities that are primarily responsible for the creation of the item.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributor</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/contributor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 14:35:55 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/contributor/</guid>
      <description>Condition Value     Definition An entity (person, organization, etc.) that has performed an important but secondary role in creating the content of the work, and is not specified in the Creator or Editor elements.   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #  Use this property to enter the names of entities that contributed to the creation of the work, but are not the primary creator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bibliographic Citation</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/bibliographic-citation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 13:48:39 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/bibliographic-citation/</guid>
      <description>Bibliographic Citation #     Condition Value     Definition A bibliographic reference for the resource. Information about a serial or about a resource from which the current Work (e.g. a book chapter) is derived.   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #  Take the Citation directly from the source if possible. For example, many Citations for academic journal articles are supplied by the publisher on a title page, in a page header or footer, or in accompanying or supplemental information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternative Title</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/alternative-title/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 13:42:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/alternative-title/</guid>
      <description>Alternative Title #     Condition Value     Definition An alternative name for the resource. Any form of the title used as a substitute or alternative to the formal title of the resource. (DCMI )   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #  Use for other forms of the title.
  For example, use for versions of the title in languages other than English.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Associated Date</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/associated-date/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 13:14:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/associated-date/</guid>
      <description>Associated Date #     Condition Value     Definition Additional date(s) associated with the resource.   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #    When used in legacy EAIC collections, this property refers to the date of an event documented in the photographic image, and later reproduced in an album or postcard.
  Record the associated date in ISO 8601 /EDTF  format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic Department</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/academic-department/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 12:59:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/academic-department/</guid>
      <description>Academic Department #     Condition Value     Definition A unit within a larger organization that addresses a specific subject or area of activity.   Required? No   Repeatable? Yes    Guidelines #  This property is intended for use with faculty, staff, and institutional publications, administrative materials, etc.
  Along with the Division and Institution properties, this value provides a consistent reference to the unit that is responsible for the creation or authorship of the resource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abstract</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/abstract/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 13:29:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/descriptive-metadata/abstract/</guid>
      <description>Abstract #     Condition Value     Definition A summary of the resource   Required? No   Repeatable? No    Guidelines #  Take the Abstract directly from the source if possible – for example, most Abstracts for academic journal articles are supplied by the publisher.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
