<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Administrative metadata on Lafayette Digital Repository Metadata Dictionary &amp; Creation Guidelines</title>
    <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/administrative-metadata/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Administrative metadata on Lafayette Digital Repository Metadata Dictionary &amp; Creation Guidelines</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 09:45:58 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/administrative-metadata/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Standard Identifier</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/administrative-metadata/standard-identifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 09:45:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/administrative-metadata/standard-identifier/</guid>
      <description>Guidelines #    The LDR accepts the following types of standard identifiers:
 DOI ISBN ISSN    From the Work dashboard, use the drop-down menu to select a prefix for the identifier. Then, enter the identifier into the form box at right.
   Handles are minted by a server attached to the repository application  A Handle ID will be created for all new items added to the LDR If a Handle already exists for the item, enter it as in the template or webform    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rights Statement</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/administrative-metadata/rights-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:55:14 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/administrative-metadata/rights-statement/</guid>
      <description>Guidelines #    Rights information may be found in the item itself, in the digital project documentation, or in accompanying or supplemental information.
  The most common right statements in the LDR are the Public Domain Mark (PDM), In Copyright, and Copyright Undetermined.
  For Faculty publications, where the copyright status of a resource is undetermined, always apply the In Copyright (InC)  rights statement.
  All Creative Commons licenses can only be applied by, or with the permission of, the rights holder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rights Holder</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/administrative-metadata/rights-holder/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:52:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/administrative-metadata/rights-holder/</guid>
      <description>Guidelines #    Establishing the identity of the Rights Holders of an item helps when a user has a question about use, reproduction, or whom to contact regarding copyright of the item.
  When entering a personal name:
→ use the name format Last, First Middle
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note</title>
      <link>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/administrative-metadata/note/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:51:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lafayettecollegelibraries.github.io/metadata-guidelines/administrative-metadata/note/</guid>
      <description>Guidelines #  This property is not visible to public users, only to internal users. To be used for any information important to internal maintenance of records or relevant to the original items, such as administrative, digitization, or decision documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
